Akash Sriram



akash.sriram@icloud.com



+91 9901777617



www.linkedin.com/in/akashsriram

About

Financial journalist specializing in equities, analysis, and real-time reporting

Skills and Aptitude

Data visualization Writing at speed Equity market analysis Source building Financial market knowledge Time management AI and coding Team work Communication skills Proactive problem solving

Education

Professional certification in Data Analytics Google, 2023

Completed a Google Data analytics professional course and gained data analytics skills using programming languages and visualization

> MA in Conflict, Development and Security University of Leeds, UK Sept 2018 - Sept 2019

Key modules of study:

- Conflict, Complex Emergencies and Global
- Governance
- Counter-terrorism
- International Political Economy

Education in Development

BA in Media Studies, Economics and Political Science

Christ University. India June 2015 - March 2018

Developed skills around international relations research, reporting and media production

Employment

Sector Specialist - Technology, Media and Telecom **Reuters News** May 2023 - Present

Led coverage of news in the tech and EV sector along with the editor in Reuters' largest bureau

Produced fast, accurate reports on tech and EV companies such as Apple, Alphabet, Tesla and Rivian

> Developed data-driven stories and provided real-time analysis on emerging trends

Built strong sourcing networks to break news and consistently outpace competitors with proactive coverage

Ideated stories to widen coverage of the team to encompass all S&P 500 companies and beyond

Developed insights on the technology sector, particularly in electric vehicles, and authored enterprise stories that deepened understanding of market dynamics

Correspondent- Technology, Media and Telecom

Reuters News

September 2021 - April 2023

Reported U.S. technology companies news specializing in electric vehicle and space firms

Demonstrated the ability to write quickly and accurately under tight deadlines, delivering real-time reports that included market analysis and updates on catalytic events

Sub Editor

Deccan Herald November 2019 - August 2021

Conceived and led digital team's 2020 US election news coverage strategy, edited stories, managed a team of sub editors, trained and mentored new team members

Experience

Co-host and Producer, The Smart Power Podcast and Around the World with POLIS

Ran a podcast on global affairs, conflict and development. Narrated audio stories of events happening around the world with guests. Founded a podcast for the School of Politics and International Studies (POLIS) at the University of Leeds

Video Production and Editing

Experienced in editing YouTube videos, short films and promotional content for events, organizations and cultural festivals on a variety of editing software